HR BUSINESS PARTNER (SUPPLY CHAIN OPERATIONS)

Summary

Manager/Human Resources Specialist Extensive background in HR leadership and People Management, leadership areas include the following areas; Engineering, Operation, Administrative, IT and large Call Centers, experience includes employee recruitment and retention, employee relations, staff development, mediation, conflict resolution, benefits and compensation, HR records management, HR policies development and legal compliance. Creation and modifications of job descriptions, market surveys and job banding. Demonstrated success in: facilitation, execution of process changes, implementation of policy and procedures, effective change agent, adaptable, flexible, ensures compliance with employment-related laws provide guidance toward increased productivity within organization.

- HR Department Startup
- Employment Law
- FMLA/ADA/EEO/FLSA/WC
- Customer Focus
- Union Avoidance
- Sourcing and Selection
- Employee Relations
- Alternative Dispute Resolution (ADR)
- Budget Management
- Project Management
- Orientation & On-Boarding
- Training & Development
- Performance Evaluations
- Cost Containments
- HR Policies & Procedures

Accomplishments

Devised a successful recruiting plan for new call centers, which resulted in sixty-four new employees in 3 -months. Participated in union contract negotiations that led to a five -year agreement prior to contract expiration. Implemented an ADP recruitment module to streamline recruitment and onboarding processes.

Experience

HR Business Partner (Supply Chain Operations), 01/2014 to Current Brookdale Senior Living i1/4 Oak Park, IL

- Provide HR project support to the Waste Managements Corporate Human Resources Group and Chief People Officer Recruited to 2-4
 month assignment helping to restructure and rewrite job titles and job descriptions for Waste Managements; Legal, Corporate
 Communications, IT and Administrative departments.
- Provide interim administrative support to the Senior Vice President of Human Resources, calendaring, locating and scheduling Executive Leadership Seminars, and review performance development summaries for signature compliance.
- Assist with notification to employee and manager regarding employees' selected for quarterly random drug testing; collaborate/mentor with Senior Corporate HR Coordinator on the 2011 Internship Program.
- Post new and replacement positions in recruiting database as needed.
- Consult and or support other projects as assigned.

Regional HR Manager, 11/2007 to 10/2013 FedEx Ground i1/4 City, STATE

- supporting 41 terminal locations, 881 employees and 9 direct reports.
- Managed a broad range of HR functions, including recruiting and training employees, administering benefits, overseeing disciplinary actions
 and managing employee relations issues/investigations, compliance and maintenance of Human Resources records, Annual filing of AAP,
 and EEO-1 reports for multi-site locations in the Gulf Coast Region (Texas, Louisiana, and Mississippi).
- Provided HR Leadership support to 881 employees of exempt and non-exempt employee's Key Results: Quickly and strategically planned
 a recruiting strategy and partnered with various temp agencies to fill urgent needs in the Gulf Region Established processes to assure that the
 organization complied with Fair Labor Standards Act {FLSA}.
- Consistently perform maintenance of human resources records.
- Implemented daily telephone conference calls with operations to assure HR was working within established guidelines and meeting forecasted timelines; and supervised the workflow of the Human Resources department.
- Co-developed company standardized disciplinary procedures and tracking system that insulated company from legal risk and ensured
 consistent and fair discipline processes.
- Devise creative and cost-effective incentive and morale-boosting programs (including special events and a tiered awards structure) that increased employee satisfaction and productivity.
- Advised managers on organizational policy such as equal employment opportunity and sexual harassment, and recommend needed changes.
- Analyzed statistical data and reports from Corporate Ethics department to identify causes of personnel issues, Provide DHRM, with suggestions and recommendations for improvement of regions' internal issues.
- Maintained records and compiled statistical reports concerning personnel-related data such as hires, transfers, performance appraisals, and absenteeism rates.
- Carefully monitored and managed GCST Regional Human Resources annual budget.

- Recruiter for Junior Field Engineers {JFEs} and Information Technology {IT} field operations.
- Support staff.
- Utilized HR knowledge and experience to assess human capital needs and collaborated with.
- Hiring managers to develop effective end-to-end recruitment sourcing and selection practices.
- Collaborate with hiring managers in the development and execution of recruiting plans to attract qualified candidates.
- Create job descriptions that accurately described the role and requirements.
- Efficiently and effectively, source for open positions.
- Conduct telephone and face-to-face interviews with clientele.
- Coordinated and implemented college recruiting initiatives; networked through industry contacts, association memberships, trade groups and employees.
- Submit resumes to hiring managers for review.
- Provide feedback to candidates, disposition appropriately, assist with offer letter and on boarding.

Manager -Benefits /Leave/STD, 08/1999 to 11/2005 AIG - AMERICAN GENERAL il/4 City, STATE

- Delivered focus on all employee service center request, for a call center team of 25 direct reports.
- Approximately 1500 US Domestic Employees Served.
- Assisted US, and Canadian employees with password reset, family status changes, {LOA, FMLA, STD, WC, Military Leave, etc...}.
- Handling employee payroll set-up, inquiries, wage garnishments and employment taxes.
- Manage the US Domestic Total Absence Management process (LOA, FMLA, STD, LTD, WC, and Military Leave) knowledgeable in additional benefits provided in such states as CA, NJ and NY.
- Manage workers' compensation employee files; collaborate with adjusters to determine employees return status, and any reasonable accommodations that may be required.
- Resolve escalated employee concerns.
- Providing and managing employee benefits and retirement programs (Medical, Dental, Visions, 401 K, Flexible Spending Accounts, Tuition Reimbursement and various other benefit plans).
- Ensuring compliance with employment-related laws (ADA, ERISA, COBRA, HIPPA, USERRA).

Education

 $Bachelor\ of\ Science: Human\ Resources\ Management\ ,\ 1992\ University\ of\ North\ Texas\ i^{1}\!\!/_{4}\ City\ ,\ State\ ,\ United\ States\ Human\ Resources\ Management$

Professional Affiliations

SHRM (Society of Human Resources Management) *ASTD (American Society of Training and Development) *HR Houston Skills

ADA, Administrative, administrative support, ADR, benefits, Budget Management, budget, call center, CA, Corporate Communications, clientele, database, Employee Relations, training employees, special events, filing, Focus, Hiring, Human Resources, HR, Information Technology, Leadership, Law, Legal, managing, mentor, organizational, payroll, performance appraisals, personnel, Policies, processes, Project Management, recruiting, recruitment, Recruiter, scheduling, Seminars, strategy, taxes, telephone, workflow